<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on G⌬RBE</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on G⌬RBE</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 12:32:06 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Configure SFTP with Chroot Jail on Debian</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/openssh/sftp-chroot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 12:32:06 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/openssh/sftp-chroot/</guid>
      <description>Setting up a chroot jail for SFTP (Secure File Transfer Protocol) on a Debian server enhances security by restricting users&amp;rsquo; access to a specific directory.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PHP-FPM Configurations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/php/php-fpm-configurations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/php/php-fpm-configurations/</guid>
      <description>PHP-FPM (FastCGI Process Manager) is an alternative PHP FastCGI implementation with some additional features useful for sites of any size, especially busier sites.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Install Redmine 4 on Debian 10</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/redmine/install-redmine-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/redmine/install-redmine-4/</guid>
      <description>Install #Instal Requirements #Passenger #Passenger will be the the application server to run Ruby on Rails app.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Create RAID0 with mdadm</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/mdadm/raid0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/mdadm/raid0/</guid>
      <description>RAID (Redundant Array of Inexpensive Disks) is a data storage virtualization technology that combines multiple physical disk drive components into one or more logical units for the purposes of data redundancy, performance improvement, or both.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LFCS Commands</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/lfcs/commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/lfcs/commands/</guid>
      <description>Commands needed for Linux Foundation Certified Sysadmin.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linux Filesystem Hierarchy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/linux/filesystem-hierarchy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/linux/filesystem-hierarchy/</guid>
      <description>UNIX-based operating systems uses one big file system tree, started with the root (/) directory.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linux processes and threads</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/linux/processes-and-threads/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/linux/processes-and-threads/</guid>
      <description>Program # a set of instructions that uses internal and/or external data internal data: strings, integers, etc&amp;hellip; external data: databases, files, etc&amp;hellip; Process vs thread #Process # an executing instance of a program each process has its own resource the same program maybe executing more than once simultaneously every process has one or more thread multi-threaded process: multiple flow of execution, every resources are shared between threads heavy weight process: a process with its own resources light weight process: a thread of a process with shared resources with other threads Thread # started from a process can share resources (eg.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linux signals</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/linux/signals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/linux/signals/</guid>
      <description>Signals # signals are used to notify processes about events in Inter Process Communication signal is an asynchronous event: not expected expected, but the time is not know signals are sent from the kernel or from a user process via system call with kill user can send signal to his own processes root can send signal to any process signals can be handled differently by the programmer or resbond acording to the system defaults two signal always use the system default: SIGKILL and SIGSTOP signal has a type and the type is indicate the meaning of the signal signals handle: exceptions detected by the hardware exceptions generated by the environment when signal sent from the kernel: the meaning attached to the signal The full list if signals is here SIGTERM: kills the process gracefully SIGKILL: kills the process immediately SIGRTMIN: no predefined purpose can be stacked, handled in FIFO Reference # LFS201 (this is just my note from LFS201, not meant to replace the original, which is explain better the above) </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MAC Address Spoofing with Network Manager</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/network-manager/mac-address-spoofing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/network-manager/mac-address-spoofing/</guid>
      <description>Spoofing MAC address is possible with Network Manager since 1.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Service Unit Configuration</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/systemd/service-unit-configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/systemd/service-unit-configuration/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR #nano /etc/systemd/system/&amp;lt;name&amp;gt;.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
